Your... revenge?
We're going to send every last one of the
scoundrels who had me executed to hell.
What?
W-Well... Who exactly are they?
I don't know.
How could I? I was set up.
I was executed for poisoning Cecilia,
but I would obviously never
resort to anything so pedestrian.
You mean... you were innocent?!
Which is why, Constance,
you will become my agent,
unmask the true culprit...
and give them a taste of hell on earth!
I c-couldn't possibly.
I know your family is in debt.
What will you do now that
you've broken off your engagement?
I didn't! That wasn't me!
You're the one who did that!
Moreover...
Does refusing to repay me
for assisting you yesterday
sound like "Grail sincerity" to you?
Wh-What would you have me do?
I b-beg your pardon
for calling so suddenly.
I've come on behalf of the Orlamundes.
Lettie is my name.
The family wishes to collect letters from
the Maurice Home for Orphaned Children
to commemorate Lady Lily's death this day.
Why, the children will be delighted.
Please, come in.
First...
You may as well begin by questioning
those who might know what happened.
S-Such as?
Let me think...
I daresay Lily Orlamunde
will prove useful.
What? Lady Lily? But she's...
Lady Lily was Lady Scarlett's friend.
Following Lady Scarlett's death,
she devoted herself to good works
to atone for her crimes.
People called her the White Lily
of Charity for her fairness.
I admired her.
But two years ago, she drank poison and
ended her own life in her family's chapel.
Her reasons remain unknown to this day.
I find that hard to believe.
That ill-natured woman
would never choose suicide.
I-Ill-natured?
Weren't the two of you
friends from childhood?
Don't suggest anything so dreadful!
I'd sooner do a handstand dance on
a cliff's edge than keep company with her!
B-But Lady Lily often visited you
in prison when no one else would.
Visited me?
Oh, those visits.
You got careless, Scarlett.
I never tried to poison Cecilia.
I don't doubt that.
But that only makes things worse.
It means someone out there is capable
of framing a woman of your caliber.
And we still haven't any idea who.
So I've come today to bid you farewell.
Loath as I am to admit it,
I think this business is beyond me.
Do forgive me.
I would have liked to aid you if possible,
but I value my own neck
far more than yours.
If she really did take her own life,
then events got out
of her control in some way.
This must have some bearing on my revenge.
My intuition tells me so.
H-How can you be so confident?
Wait for me!
You're too fast for us!
Here.
Thank you all for these letters.
I'll see that they reach Lady Lily.
Great.
Hey.
We'd better hurry back, George.
Yeah. I know, Tony.
Bye, miss!
Our next visit will be
to the scene of Lily's suicide.
I trust you remember what to do, girl.
I'm so sorry. We only have habits.
No, this will do nicely.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me. I'm from the Maurice
Home for Orphaned Children.
In memory of Lady Lily...
Come in. It's right this way.
Thank you very much.
I th-thought I would die of fright.
Nevertheless, everything went swimmingly.
This is where Lady Lily met her end.
Over here, I suspect.
Wait...
What are you doing, girl?
Well, I really ought to pray for her.
Nonsense. Prayers wouldn't please her.
Lily...
would tell you to hurry up and find out
the truth in that snide way of hers.
I'm certain she left a clue somewhere,
and in some infuriating place
that no one would think to check.
Could it be... behind the picture frame?
That would be just like her.
Wh-What a sacrilegious hiding place.
What's this?
There's really something here!
Hide it!
R-Right!
Wha...
What are you doing here,
Randolph Ulster?!
Lily was married?
Yes. To Earl Randolph Ulster
of the House of Richelieu.
Randolph? That hidebound stick-in-the-mud?
You know him?
He's my nemesis.
People call him "Lord Death."
I beg your pardon. You're from
the Maurice Home for Orphaned Children?
Y-Yes. M-My name is Lettie.
I've, um, only just started there.
I see. I often played
with a little redheaded boy there.
George, I think his name was.
Is he well?
O-Of cou—
Wait. We just visited
the orphanage, remember?
George had chestnut hair.
The redheaded boy that age
was most certainly Tony.
Um... Could you be thinking
of Tony, perhaps?
There's a younger boy named George,
but he has chestnut hair.
Why, yes. I did mean Tony.
How rude of me.
E-Everyone makes mistakes.
Well, if you'll excuse me...
Sister.
The roads are perilous
for a woman walking alone.
If you permit it,
I shall see you to the orphanage.
Th-That's all right!
I, er, have an errand to run.
Although I do appreciate your offer.
So, good day to you, my lord.
I was scared stiff!
I've never met anyone so intimidating.
D-Do you think he suspects me?
I wonder.
That man has always had a keener nose
than was good for him.
You should have gotten rid of those rags.
When the nuns were nice enough
to lend them to me?
Kiriki kirikuku.
K-Kirikuki...?
See? I told you so.
You always worry too much, Tony.
Shove it. What do you care?
Tell me, what was that?
A spell.
A spell?
Yeah. For spotting bad guys.
Lady Lily taught it to us.
She did? When?
Before she died.
"Kiriki kirikuku."
If anything should happen to me
and people come asking
about me, recite this spell.
If they react to it at all,
you'll know they're very bad people.
If that happens, we're supposed to
round up everybody and run for it.
What does this mean?
Could it be...
Lady Lily was murdered?
I'm exhausted.
Shall we open it?
A key?
It says...
"Destroy the Holy Grail of Eris."
The Holy Grail of Eris?
What on earth does that mean?
Don't ask me.
The paper itself looks like part
of a pamphlet for sightseers.
Eris is the goddess of discord
and strife in the Myth of Faris.
She is a wicked deity.
They say she drove a nation to ruin.
That's a legend from
Adelbide's neighboring land.
"Eris" is also the name I used
whenever I wanted to sample the nightlife.
I-I see.
Now, what about the key?
Well...
It has a number on it, but nothing
to indicate which workshop it was made in.
I don't think we have enough clues
to figure out what it's for.
True. Still...
she was no normal woman.
Should you be out and about so soon?
After ending your engagement like that.
That's right. I did end my engagement.
The party even made it into the papers.
The papers?!
"Poor Constance Grail proves even a lamb
will charge a hound when provoked."
Or so the Mayflower's
editorial opined yesterday.
O-Oh dear.
And they say Pamela went back
to her family's domain the next day.
It's "for her health," but anyone can see
she ran with her tail between her legs.
You don't say...
As for Neil,
the Bronson Company's aristocratic
clients have started a boycott.
Oh, speaking of which,
Neil came to apologize
and ask my forgiveness this morning.
I told him how to stop
the people coming after them,
so that should die down soon.
I'm sure he was only thinking of himself.
Maybe, but he did apologize,
even if he didn't mean it.
Besides, Neil was the one responsible.
The people who work for
the Bronson Company did nothing wrong.
Connie, you're sincere to a fault.
Listen to her! You should
never have forgiven him.
Still, Connie...
You've become an overnight
celebrity, so be careful.
I mean, where were you yesterday?
Well, um, I wanted to be alone, so...
It's quite all right.
I won't pry until
you feel like telling me.
So...
you'd better come to me
when you need help.
Kate!
Anyway, infidelity is just despicable!
I suppose you'll want nothing
to do with men for—
My. Isn't this...
Aha. I see how it is.
You're already looking to the future!
This invitation here.
I hear lots of good-looking folks
attend Emilia Godwin's balls.
Wait, Kate...
I don't blame you, Connie!
I read in a novel that only new love
can heal a broken heart!
I hope you find someone special!
It's not like—
Go for it, Connie!
Sh-She's got some strange idea
in her head.
What is this card?
Her invitations are
as tasteless as I remember.
I'm sure she wants you to spark gossip.
You did cause a scandal.
Are you acquainted with Baroness Godwin?
Yes, I know her well.
We shall be attending
Emilia's ball, Constance!
She loves nothing more than talk
and the misfortune of others.
It's been ten years,
but if we play our cards right,
she'll sing for us like
a canary in mating season.
Are you ready, Constance?
We have a delightful party ahead of us.
Good evening, Emilia.
Good evening, Aisha.
And who might this be?
My special someone.
I-I see...
Why, good evening.
Gracious. What a disappointment.
She seems more refined than before,
but she's still a far cry from Scarlett.
Thank you very much for inviting me
this evening, Lady Godwin.
What a lovely dress you're wearing.
With your hair like sunflowers,
it suits you perfectly.
H-Huh? Did I say something wrong?
But I did just what you told me to...
Dear me.
She's just as timid as I remember.
What now? Emilia left.
My!
There's Aisha Spencer.
How she's changed.
What perfect timing.
I have business with her.
Go see what she has to say.
I-It's him!
L-L-Lady Scarlett, this is your cue!
Uh, I think not! I can't stand that man!
What?!
How nice to see you again, sister.
I th-think you have the wrong person.
Do I?
Just the other day, I met a nun
who spoke with no accent,
had unblemished hands,
and curtsied like a lady.
In addition...
she had hazel hair
and bright green eyes just like you.
C-Coincidences do happen.
In that case, I'll be direct,
Constance Grail.
What are you after?
What did you take from the chapel?
My late wife's will? Or something else?
Oh, no, you see...
S-Somebody save me!
Oh, honestly! Must I do everything?
Stand aside,
Constance!
What's the matter?
You sound terribly certain.
I trust you have proof, then.
Lady Scarlett!
Surely you wouldn't treat a delicate girl
like a thief without good reason.
I can't think what I've done
to deserve such an insult.
Then shall we pay the Maurice Home
for Orphaned Children another visit?
If they can confirm
you are not the same Lettie who
came on behalf of the Orlamundes,
I will admit that I was mistaken.
He knows everything!
I must decline.
While I'm honored by your interest,
I value myself too highly to arrange
a date with a gentleman I've just met.
She brought it on herself, the whore!
She took my husband!
Wh-Who are they?
Teresa Jennings and Margot Tudor.
It would seem Teresa was having
an affair with Margot's husband.
What?!
The wound doesn't look deep.
Are you all right?
We should still clean it to be safe.
I won't pursue the matter further today.
That said...
Can you honestly tell me
you aren't involved?
So much for that party.
And here I'd hoped
to question Emilia and Aisha.
You remind me of someone.
Only you look nothing like her.
Silly, isn't it?
You mean Scarlett Castiel?
I suppose saying such things
to an ordinary girl like you
will earn me another tongue-lashing.
Ten years ago,
why was Scarlett put to death?
Do you know?
Because she tried to poison
Crown Princess Cecilia.
Still...
You really do remind me of her.
The seventh division of inmest Mars.
At the old Montrose residence.
The invitation...
is in Earl John Doe's hat.
The winners in life are those who survive.
So take care that you aren't forced
to make an early exit, Constance Grail.
Kiriki kirikuku.
AN EXTRAORDINARY VILLAINESS
AND AN ORDINARY GIRL
Translation:
William Varteresian
Subtitle Timing:
Edgar Cruz
Subtitle Editing:
Riley Dalton
Quality Check:
SMR
Translation Check:
Sriram Gurunathan